A Guide to the William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004 FA448
Rockefeller Archive Center
William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004
1870s-1922
1860s-1975 (Bulk: 1870s-1922)
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, William
McAlpin, Emma Rockefeller
Dodge, Geraldine R. (Geraldine Rockefeller) (1882-1973)
FA448
9.98 Cubic Feet 31 containers
Approximately 1,200 prints
Arrangement
Rockefeller family photographic holdings are arranged into the following series: Rockefeller family and Avery family photographs, Series 1001. William Avery Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1002. John D. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1003. William Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1004. John D. Rockefeller Jr. family photographs, Series 1005. Pocantico Hills photographs, Series 1006. John D. Rockefeller 3rd family photographs, Series 1007. Nelson A. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1008. Laurance S. Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1009. David Rockefeller family photographs, Series 1010.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Collection includes individual and group portraits of immediate family, family homes, as well as images of relatives and extended family.
Arrangement
The William Rockefeller family photographs are arranged primarily by family member, and then further arranged by format: prints, albums and oversized.
Photographs
- William Rockefeller family photographs, 1004; 9.98 Cubic Feet 31 containers
  Arrangement
  This series contains 6 subseries:
  1004A Louis Edward Rockefeller. 1004B Emma Rockefeller McAlpin family. 1004C William Goodsell Rockefeller family. 1004D John Davison Rockefeller II. 1004E Percy Avery Rockefeller family. 1004F Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge family.
  For ease of access the material is further arranged by: Prints (Boxes P 1, P 2, P 3, etc.). Albums (Boxes A 1, A 2, A 3, etc.). Oversized (Boxes: O 1, O 2, O 3, C 1, C 2, C 3, etc.).
  - Prints
    - Almira Geraldine Goodsell Rockefeller, 6 prints (Box P 43)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 12 prints (Box P 43)
    - Friends, 6 prints (Box P 43)
    - Homes, 18 prints (Box P 43)
    - Homes - Rockwood Hall, 15 prints comprising 2 full panoramic views (Box P 157, Folder 10)
    - Relatives, 18 prints (Box P 44)
    - William Rockefeller, 1880s-1921; 14 prints (Box P 44)
  - Albums
    - Homes - Rockwood Hall, 35 prints (Box A 1)
    - Homes - Rockwood Hall, 1922; 50 prints (Box A 2)
    - Webster Album, 1967 (Box A 3)
  - Oversized
    - William Rockefeller family, 36 prints (Box O 1)
    - William Rockefeller family (Box O 6)
    - Almira Geraldine Goodsell Rockefeller, 2 prints (Box O 3)
    - Almira Geraldine Goodsell Rockefeller, 1 print (Box O 4)
    - Almira Geraldine Goodsell Rockefeller, 2 prints (Box O 7)
    - Almira Geraldine Goodsell Rockefeller (Box C 6)
    - Group Portraits, 6 prints (Box O 2)
    - Group Portraits (Box C 6)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 3 prints (Box O 3)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 3 prints (Box O 4)
    - Group Portraits - Family, 1 print (Box O 7)
    - Group Portraits - Family and Friends, 1 print (Box O 4)
    - Homes - Rockwood Hall - Barn, 1 print (Box O 2)
    - Homes - Rockwood Hall, 2 prints (Box O 7)
    - Relatives, 4 prints (Box O 7)
    - William Rockefeller, 4 prints (Box O 2)
    - William Rockefeller, 4 prints (Box O 3)
    - William Rockefeller, 2 prints (Box O 4)
    - William Rockefeller, 2 prints (Box O 7)
  - Louis Edward Rockefeller, 1004A; 3 prints
    - Prints
      - Louis Edward Rockefeller, 3 prints (Box P 44)
  - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin family, 1004B; 428 prints
    - Prints
      - Albums - Camping Trip, 14 prints (Box P 45)
      - Dr. David Hunter McAlpin Jr., 10 prints (Box P 45)
      - David Hunter McAlpin III family - David Hunter McAlpin III, 1 print (Box P 45)
      - David Hunter McAlpin III family - Group Portraits, 1 print (Box P 45)
      - Elaine Rockefeller McAlpin Tate, 6 prints (Box P 45)
      - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin, 12 prints (Box P 45)
      - Geraldine R. McAlpin Webster family - Geraldine R. McAlpin Webster, 15 prints (Box P 45)
      - Geraldine R. McAlpin Webster family - Group Portraits, 1949-1962; 8 prints (Box P 46)
      - Group Portraits, 6 prints (Box P 46)
      - Homes, 24 prints (Box P 46)
        Scope and Contents
        Morris Plains, NJ
      - Informals - Travel, 1 print (Box P 47)
      - Relatives, 1 print (Box P 47)
      - William Rockefeller McAlpin family - Group Portraits, 2 prints (Box P 47)
      - William Rockefeller McAlpin family - Sylvia McAlpin Walsh, 1 print (Box P 47)
      - William Rockefeller McAlpin family - William Rockefeller McAlpin, 9 prints (Box P 47)
      - William Rockefeller McAlpin family - William Rockefeller McAlpin Jr., 1 print (Box P 47)
    - Albums
      - Webster Album, 1-38 (Box A 4)
      - Webster Album, 39-72 (Box A 5)
      - Webster Album, 73-95 (Box A 6)
      - Geraldine R. McAlpin (Webster) - Miscellaneous, 1920-1924; 200 prints (Box A 7)
    - Oversized
      - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin family, Approximately 10 prints (Box O 5)
      - Emma Rockefeller McAlpin family, 11 prints (Box O 8)
  - William Goodsell Rockefeller family, 1004C; 20 prints
    - Prints
      - Relatives, 20 prints (Box P 47)
  - John Davison Rockefeller II, 1004D; 2 prints
    - Prints
      - John Davison Rockefeller II, 2 prints (Box P 48)
  - Percy Avery Rockefeller family, 1004E; Approximately 100 prints.
    - Prints
      - Group Portrait, 1 print (Box P 48)
      - Isabel G. Stillman Rockefeller, 3 prints (Box P 48)
      - Percy Avery Rockefeller, 6 prints (Box P 48)
    - Albums
      - Camping Album, A and B, 51 prints (Box A 8)
      - Wedding Album and newspaper clippings (Box A 9)
    - Oversized
      - Group Portraits - Family and Friends, 2 prints (Box O 4)
      - Homes, 3 prints (Box O 2)
      - Homes, 4 prints (Box O 9)
      - Isabel G. Stillman Rockefeller (Box C 6)
  - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge family, 1004F; Approximately 220 prints
    - Prints
      - Group Portraits, 7 prints (Box P 48)
      - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge, 34 prints (Box P 48)
      - Homes - Giralda, 1975; 41 prints (Box P 49)
      - Homes - Giralda, 41 prints (Box P 50)
      - Homes - Giralda, 36 prints (Box P 51)
      - Homes - Dodge Mansion, New York City, 9 prints (Box P 52)
      - Marcellus Hartley Dodge, 2 prints (Box P 52)
      - Marcellus Hartley Dodge Jr., 10 prints (Box P 52)
      - Travel - Versailles, 17 prints (Box P 52)
    - Oversized
      - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge family (Madison Municipal Buildings), 2 prints (Box O 4)
      - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge family, 10 prints (Box O 10)
        Portraits and homes
      - Ethel Geraldine Rockefeller Dodge family, 10 prints (Box O 4)
      - Unlabeled, undated (Box O 4)